Guide to the Gravity Probe B records SC1274
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Gravity Probe B records
1983-2008
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University. Department of Physics
SC1274
44.75 Linear Feet 31 boxes
Biographical / Historical
Gravity Probe B was a relativity gyroscope experiment funded by NASA and led by the Stanford University Department of Physics, with Lockheed Martin as the primary subcontractor. Mission scientists viewed it as the second gravity experiment in space, following the successful launch of Gravity Probe A (GP-A) in 1976. For more information, see: http://einstein.stanford.edu/.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Scope and Contents
Records include audiovisual materials, administrative records pertaining to the project, photographs, and public relations materials.
Arrangement
The records are arranged in four series: audiovisual recordings; administrative records; photographs; and public relations materials.
Gravitation theory.; Spacecraft design.; Technology assessment.; Stanford University. Department of Physics; Stanford University. Department of Physics
- Audiovisual recordings
  - The Gravity Probe B Experiment, 2004; b1_1; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - Documentation Repository, undated; b1_2; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - The Gravity Probe B Experiment, 2004; b1_3; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - Gravity Probe B - Stanford University, 2001 Aug 20; b1_4; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - Telescope, undated; b1_5; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Gravity Probe B Interview, undated; b1_6; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - GP-B 1999-7-A, 2002 Jan 29; b1_7; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - GP-B 1999-7-B, 2002 Jan 29; b1_8; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - GP-B 1999-11-A, 2002 Jan 29; b1_9; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Moc Sim 5, undated; b1_10; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - FQH44 Bore #3, 1999 Mar 20; b1_11; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Bore #4, 1999 Mar 23; b1_12; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Gp-B Gyro Integration, undated; b1_13; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - GPB Dub, undated; b1_14; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Gyro #1 FQH61, undated; b1_15; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - System Engineering Aspects GP-Flight Program, undated; b1_16; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - SGS Operations Oasis, 1998 Mar 27; b1_17; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - GP-B Mission Select Reel, undated; b1_18; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
  - TDRSS Orientation, undated; b1_19; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Gravity Probe-B Launch VAFB California, 2004 Apr 22; b2_1; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - University Communications, undated; b2_2; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - University Communications, undated; b2_3; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Gravity B Tape #1, 2006 May 18; b2_4; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Gravity B Tape #2, 2006 May 18; b2_5; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Gravity B Tape #3, 2006 May 18; b2_6; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - T. Kolkhorst "GPB", 2003 Feb 14; b2_7; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - BDM-NASA Hubble Space Telescope, 1990 Apr 27; b2_8; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - ABC Television Copyright Footage, undated; b2_9; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - ABC Television Copyright Footage, undated; b2_10; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - ABC Television Copyright Footage, undated; b2_11; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - ABC Television Copyright Footage, undated; b2_12; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Gravity Probe - B Customer Flow Tape, 2004 Apr 20; b2_13; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - NASA Television Coverage of GP - B Launch Edited, 2004 Apr 20; b2_14; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Spinup System, undated; b2_15; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Overview, undated; b2_16; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - End to End Error Analysis, undated; b2_17; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Testing Einstein's Universe, 2003 Sep 19; b2_18; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Attitude and Translational Control Systems, 1985 May 9; b2_19; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Readout System, undated; b2_20; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Gyro Manufacture and Metrology, undated; b2_21; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Gravity Probe B Movie, 2001 Feb; b2_22; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Is There an American Stonehenge?, undated; b2_23; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - GP-B Integration, 1999 Mar; b2_24; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - GP-B Final Inspect, undated; b2_25; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Gravity Probe B Probe Neck Tube, 1988 Oct 18; b3_1; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 3)
  - Lockheed Martin Missiles and Space, 1995 Apr 4; b3_2; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 3)
  - System Engineering Aspects GP-Flight Program, undated; b3_3; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 3)
  - "le sniff d'amour einstein a-t-il raison?", 2004 Jan 9; b3_4; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 3)
  - The Assembly and the Test of the Hubble Space Telescope, 1987 Jun; b3_5; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 3)
  - Gravity Probe B Separation Tests, undated; b3_6; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 3)
  - NASA Release Hubble Space Telescope, 1990 Mar 21; b3_7; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 3)
  - GP-B Sim7 Mock Press Interviews, 2003 Sep 23; b3_8; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 3)
  - GP-B Space Vehicle, 1997 Apr; b3_9; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 3)
  - SLA Probe, 1999 Apr; b3_10; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 3)
  - GP-B Mission, 2003 Mar 14; b3_11; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 3)
  - Gravity Probe B Dr. Everitt, 2002 Dec 20; b3_12; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 3)
  - Gravity Probe B Space Vehicle, 2005 Jun 20; b3_13; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 3)
  - GP-B Space Vehicle Highlight, 2005 Jun 20; b3_14; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 3)
  - The Relativity Mission, undated; b3_15; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 3)
  - Gravity Probe B, undated; b3_16; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 3)
  - Peter Lindener, undated; b3_17; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 3)
  - B-102 Shaker Test, 1995 Mar 17; b3_18; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 3)
  - Gravity Probe B Relativity Mission, 1998; b3_19; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 3)
  - Gravity Probe B, 1999; b3_20; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 3)
  - SIM 6 Press Conference, 2003 Aug 6; b3_21; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 3)
  - Gravity Probe B Movie, undated; b3_22; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 3)
  - The Advanced X-Ray Astrophysics Facility, undated; b3_23; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 3)
  - "Exploring the Depth of the Universe", 1990 Mar 21; b3_24; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 3)
  - System Engineering Aspects GP-Flight Program Tape 2, undated; b3_25; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 3)
  - GP-B Spacecraft Training for Mission Operations, undated; b4_1; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 4)
  - Gravity Probe B, undated; b4_2; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 4)
  - Gravity Probe B SIM6 Debriefing, 2003 Aug 8; b4_3; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 4)
  - SR 190619 "Blackholes" Reel 17, undated; b4_4; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 4)
  - Briefing Thatcher Meriwether, 2002 Aug 28; b4_5; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 4)
  - GP-B Spacecraft Training for Mission Operations, undated; b4_6; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 4)
  - Gravity Probe B Training Session - Mission Timeline, undated; b4_7; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 4)
  - SGS Operations Oasis Training, 1998 Mar 26; b4_8; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 4)
  - GMOTI: Kickoff, 2002 May 5; b4_9; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 4)
  - SR 190619 "Blackholes" Reel 19, undated; b4_10; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 4)
  - GP-B Final Inspection, undated; b4_11; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 4)
  - SGS Operations Oasis Training, 1998 Mar 26; b4_12; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 4)
  - Gravity Probe B - Simulated News Conference, undated; b4_13; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 4)
  - testing Einstein's Universe - The Gravity Probe B Program, Director's Cut, 0; b4_14; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 4)
  - Gravity Probe B, 1999; b4_15; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 4)
  - GP-B, undated; b4_16; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 4)
  - Dan Debra Measurment and Error, undated; b4_17; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 4)
  - SGS Operations Oasis CC Training, 1998 Mar 26; b4_18; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 4)
  - GMOT 5: Anomaly Response, undated; b4_19; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 4)
  - GMOT 4: TCAD, 2002 Jun 27; b4_20; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 4)
  - QB to Spider Assy, undated; b4_21; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 4)
  - Bore #2, 1999 Mar 24; b4_22; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 4)
  - SLA Probe, 1999; b4_23; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 4)
  - Channel 7 Newscast, undated; b5_1; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
  - Gravity Probe B, 1999; b5_2; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
  - GP-B Integration, 1999 Mar; b5_3; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
  - FQH44, 1999 Mar 20; b5_4; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
  - GP-B Spacecraft, undated; b5_5; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
  - GP-B Mission Selects Master Set, undated; b5_6; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
  - QB to Spider Assy, undated; b5_7; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
  - Gravity Probe - B, 2005 Sep 13; b5_8; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
  - Gravity Probe B Relativity Mission, 1998; b5_9; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
  - GP-B Payload Award Fee, 1997; b5_10; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
  - G-BP 1999-5-A, b5_11; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
  - NASA Export Control Program, undated; b5_12; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
  - GP-B Payload Award Fee, 1997; b5_13; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
  - Castelo Gondolfo, 1990; b5_14; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
  - GP-B Spacecraft, 1997 Aug 27; b5_15; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
  - Stanford Integrity Beacon, undated; b5_16; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
  - Probe Flight Operations Equipment Training, undated; b5_17; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
  - Probe Flight Operations Equipment Training, undated; b5_18; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
  - Probe Flight Operations Equipment Training, undated; b5_19; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
  - Gravity Probe-B Customer Flow Tape, 2004 Apr 20; b5_20; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
  - Black Holes, 1998; b5_21; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
  - Territoires Einstien a-t-il raison?, undated; b5_22; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
  - FQH-51 R S, undated; b5_23; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
  - Gravity Probe B, 1999; b5_24; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
  - Ed Mark, undated; b5_25; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
  - GP-B Spacecraft Highlights, undated; b5_26; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
  - GP-B Spacecraft Award Fee, 1997; b5_27; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 5)
  - Probe Arrival, 1990 Jan 30; b6_1; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 6)
  - GP-B Spacecraft Award Fee, 1997; b6_2; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 6)
  - Gyro, undated; b6_3; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 6)
  - Gyro Loopez Fault Analysis, undated; b6_4; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 6)
  - Inspection: Rotor 95525, 2001 Jul 16; b6_5; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 6)
  - Bore #2, 1999 Mar 24; b6_6; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 6)
  - Probe - C Manufacturing, 1997 Jul; b6_7; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 6)
  - IBLS, undated; b6_8; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 6)
  - Gravity Probe B Space Vehicle Highlights, 1998; b6_9; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 6)
  - Telescope, undated; b6_10; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 6)
  - Gravity Probe B Video File, 2003 Nov 4; b6_11; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 6)
  - GP-B 1999-7-B, undated; b6_12; 0 (Box 6)
  - GP-B 1999-6-A, undated; b6_13; 0 (Box 6)
  - FQH-595, undated; b6_14; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 6)
  - Protective Cover Frame Proof Loads and Assy Ops, 2003 Sep; b6_15; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 6)
  - Gyro #1 FQh61, undated; b6_16; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 6)
  - GP-B Gyro Integration, undated; b6_17; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 6)
  - GP-B 1999-11-A, 2002 Jan 29; b6_18; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 6)
  - "Blackholes" U.S. Shoot, undated; b6_19; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 6)
  - "Blackholes" U.S. Shoot, undated; b6_20; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 6)
  - Bore #4, 1999 Mar 23; b6_21; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 6)
  - Everett Faculty Seminar in Faculty Club on Space and Technology, 1996 Oct 15; b6_22; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 6)
  - Everett Faculty Seminar in Faculty Club on Space and Technology Tape 2, 1996 Oct 10; b6_23; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 6)
  - Gravity Probe B Relativity Mission, undated; b6_24; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 6)
  - GP-B 1999-7-A, 2002 Jan 29; b6_25; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 6)
  - Bomarzo, undated; b6_26; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 6)
  - Gravity Probe B Award, 1999; b6_27; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 6)
  - Gravity Probe - B, 2003 Nov 6; b7_1; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 7)
  - Gravity Probe - B, 2004 Mar 3; b7_2; 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp) (Box 7)
  - Gravity Probe - B, 2004 Mar 3; b7_3; 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp) (Box 7)
  - GPB Movie WND, 2002 Apr; b7_4; 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp) (Box 7)
  - Gravity Probe B "Testing Einstein's Universe", 2006 May 27; b7_5; 0 (Box 7)
  - GP-B Mission, 2003 Mar 14; b7_6; 0 (Box 7)
  - NASA Television Coverage of GP-B Launch, 2004 Apr 20; b7_7; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 7)
  - "Black Holes" Reel 18, undated; b7_8; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 7)
  - GPB Aerial Tests (Long version), undated; b7_9; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 7)
  - Gravity Probe B Customer Flow Tape, 2004 Apr 20; b7_10; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 7)
  - Aircheck - Silicon Valley Business, 1996 Jun 9; b7_11; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 7)
  - NASA Televisin Coverage of GP-B Launch "Edited", 2004 Apr 20; b7_12; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 7)
  - Interview - Rex Geveden, 2002 Nov; b7_13; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 7)
  - Black Holes, undated; b7_14; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 7)
  - Gravity Probe - B Launch, 2004 Apr 20; b7_15; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 7)
  - Gravity Probe - B Launch, 2004 Apr 20; b7_16; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 7)
  - Gravity Probe - B Launch Video, 2004 Jun 9; b7_17; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 7)
  - Peter Linderer - DSP, undated; b7_18; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 7)
  - "Blackholes" U.S. Shoot - "Exploratorium", undated; b7_19; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 7)
  - GP-B on ABC World News Tonight, 2004 Apr 18; b7_20; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 7)
  - Gravity Probe B - Launch Video, 2004 Jun 9; b7_21; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 7)
  - Probe C Thermal Anomaly Redesign Operations, 2000 May 4; b7_22; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 7)
  - Stanford Aerial Footage Window Dub, undated; b7_23; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 7)
  - HEPL End Station #1, undated; b7_24; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 7)
  - Gravity Probe B Movie, 2001 Feb; b7_25; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 7)
  - Gravity Probe B Video File, 2005 Sep 13; b7_26; 0 (Box 7)
  - GP-B Final Inspect, undated; b7_27; 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp) (Box 7)
  - Lockheed Martin Missiles and Space, 1995 Apr 19; b8_1; 0 (Box 8)
  - Probe Neck Fabrication, undated; b8_2; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 8)
  - Spacecraft Development, 1993 May 20; b8_3; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 8)
  - GP-B Integration, 1999 Mar; b8_4; 0 (Box 8)
  - GMOT 2: Mission Planning, 2002 May 23; b8_5; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 8)
  - Training, 2002 Jul 3; b8_6; 0 (Box 8)
  - SGS Operations - Oasis-CC Training: Operations, 1998 Mar 27; b8_7; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 8)
  - Briefing - Orbit Determination, 2002 Jul 31; b8_8; 0 (Box 8)
  - GMOT 3: Management, 2002 Jun 13; b8_9; 0 (Box 8)
  - Ground Data Systems, 2002 Aug 14; b8_10; 0 (Box 8)
  - GP-B 1999-6-6A, 2002 Jan 29; b8_11; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 8)
  - Gravity Probe BL Intereview Francis Everitt, undated; b8_12; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 8)
  - Testing Einstein in Space: Gravity Probe B Mission, 2006 May 18; b8_13; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 8)
  - Gravity Probe B, 2003 Nov 2; b8_14; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 8)
  - MOC Sim 5, undated; b8_15; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 8)
  - Gravity Probe B, 2003 Nov 8; b8_16; 0 (Box 8)
  - GPB Integration, 1999 May; b9_1; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 9)
  - Not labeled, undated; b9_2; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 9)
  - Isaac/6P B, undated; b9_3; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 9)
  - GPB 1999-7-B, b9_4; 1 videotape(s) (digital) (Box 9)
  - CWF Everittt, 1983; b9_5; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 9)
  - GPB Move, undated; b9_6; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 9)
  - Gyro and Tele Integration, undated; b9_7; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 9)
  - Hex, undated; b9_8; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 9)
  - FQH Benz, 1999 Mar 20; b9_9; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 9)
  - GP-B Final Inspect, undated; b9_10; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 9)
  - m006/GMA Ship, undated; b9_11; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 9)
  - Gp-B 1999-6-B, 2000 Feb; b9_12; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 9)
  - Telescope, undated; b9_13; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 9)
  - SLA Probe, 1999 Apr; b9_14; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 9)
  - Gyro extraction, undated; b9_15; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 9)
  - GPB-A, 1999; b9_16; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 9)
  - Gp-B Move, undated; b9_17; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 9)
  - Gyro Insta, undated; b9_18; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 9)
  - FQH Benz, undated; b9_19; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 9)
  - BORE #4, 1999 Mar 23; b9_20; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 9)
  - ? -02, undated; b9_21; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 9)
  - BORE #2, 1999 Mar 24; b9_22; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 9)
  - QB to Spider, undated; b9_23; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 9)
  - ? -01, undated; b9_24; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 9)
  - ? -03, undated; b9_25; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 9)
  - GP-B 1999-11-A, b9_26; 1 videotape(s) (digital) (Box 9)
  - Gp-B 1999-7-A, b9_27; 1 videotape(s) (digital) (Box 9)
  - GP-B 1999-12-A, b9_28; 1 videotape(s) (digital) (Box 9)
  - Gyro #1, undated; b9_29; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 9)
  - Window #1 Contaminations, undated; b9_30; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 9)
  - Gyro 4 Insta 8-14, undated; b9_31; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 9)
  - GP-B 1999-5A, b9_32; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 9)
  - Tom Langenstein - Stanford Gravity Probe, 2003 Jun 11; b10_1; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - Gravity Probe B, 2002 Nov 19; b10_2; 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp) (Box 10)
  - Testing Einstein in Space: Gravity Probe B Program, 2003 Sep 19; b10_3; 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp) (Box 10)
  - Stanford University Gravity Probe B "Testing Einstein's Universe", undated; b10_4; 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp) (Box 10)
  - Gravity Probe B Video File, undated; b10_5; 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp) (Box 10)
  - Gravity Probe B (rev 2), 2003 Feb; b10_6; 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp) (Box 10)
  - Gravity Probe B Commemorative Launch Video, 2004 Jun; b10_7; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - Stanford Integrity Beacon, undated; b10_8; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - Gravity Probe B Video File, 2003 Nov 4; b10_9; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - Shifting Our Perspective - The Chandra X-ray Telescope, 2002 Nov 22; b10_10; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - Testing Einstein's Universe: The Gravity Probe B Program "Director's Cut", 2003 Jul 9; b10_11; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - Gravity Probe - B Video File, 2005 Sep 13; b10_12; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - Bill Nye the Science Guy, undated; b10_13; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - End to End Error, undated; b10_14; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - Attitude Control - In Flight Callibration of Instrument, undated; b10_15; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - Australian Broadcasting Corp - Stanford Sequences Roll, undated; b10_16; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - Suspension System, undated; b10_17; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - Overview/Gyro Design, undated; b10_18; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - Gravity Probe B B-roll, undated; b10_19; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - Science Data - Instrum. Sys., undated; b10_20; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - Stanford Includes Airport Conference, 1994 Oct 18; b10_21; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - Gravity Probe B - Launch Video, 2004 Jun 14; b10_22; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - Gravity Probe B, 2003 Sep 5; b10_23; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - "Black Holes" copy, 2005 Jun 20; b10_24; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - Black Holes - Pioneer Productions for Channel 4, undated; b10_25; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - GP-B Stanford University Hardward Development, 2005 Jun 8; b11_1; 1 videotape(s) (video8) (Box 11)
  - BOB Day of Las Alamos Talk on Optical Methods, 1987 Jun 29; b11_2; 1 videotape(s) (video8) (Box 11)
  - TJ Quinn, undated; b11_3; 1 videotape(s) (video8) (Box 11)
  - FIST, undated; b11_4; 1 videotape(s) (video8) (Box 11)
  - Includes Interviews and B-roll of Spacecraft, 2003 Nov 4; b11_5; 1 videotape(s) (dvcam) (Box 11)
  - Gravity Prob B Video File, undated; b11_6; 1 videotape(s) (dvcam) (Box 11)
  - Gravity Probe B, 2004 Mar 3; b11_7; 1 videotape(s) (dvcam) (Box 11)
  - Gravity Probe B, 2004 Mar 3; b11_8; 1 videotape(s) (dvcam) (Box 11)
  - GP-B Media Training, 2007 Mar 26; b11_9; 1 videotape(s) (dvcam) (Box 11)
  - GP-B Afternoon Training, 2007 Mar 26; b11_10; 1 videotape(s) (dvcam) (Box 11)
  - Includes Interviews and B-roll of Spacecraft, 2003 Nov 10; b11_11; 1 videotape(s) (dvcam) (Box 11)
  - Gravity Probe B, undated; b11_12; 1 videotape(s) (dvcam) (Box 11)
  - DAN DeBra in GPB Conference, undated; b11_13; 1 videotape(s) (video8) (Box 11)
  - Brums/Data, 1993 Apr 12; b11_14; 1 videotape(s) (video8) (Box 11)
  - GP-B Stanford University Hardward Development, 2005 Jun 8; b11_15; 1 videotape(s) (video8) (Box 11)
  - Professor Moffet's 1st Talk, 2005 Jun 9; b11_16; 1 videotape(s) (video8) (Box 11)
  - Ori's Going Away Lunch, undated; b11_17; 1 videotape(s) (video8) (Box 11)
  - Spinnning Gyro, undated; b11_18; 1 videotape(s) (video8) (Box 11)
  - Gravity Probe B, 2002 Oct 28; b11_19; 1 videotape(s) (dvcam) (Box 11)
  - Gravity Probe B Video File, 2005 Sep 13; b11_20; 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp) (Box 11)
  - Gravity Probe B Video File, 2005 Sep 13; b11_21; 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp) (Box 11)
  - GP-B Resource Reel, 2007 Apr 11; b11_22; 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp) (Box 11)
  - Gravity Probe B Video File, 2004 Mar 3; b11_23; 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp) (Box 11)
  - Gravity Probe B Press Briefing, 2004 Apr 2; b11_24; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 11)
  - Gravity Probe B, 2004 Apr 2; b11_25; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 11)
  - Gravity Probe B, 2004 Apr 2; b11_26; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 11)
  - Gravity Probe B, 2003 Nov 4; b11_27; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 11)
  - KSC Edited Launched Footage, 2003 Nov 6; b11_28; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 11)
  - NASA Radio Presentation: The Space Story SS 1236-1239, undated; b30_1; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 30)
  - CP Snow: The role of personality in science, 1970; b30_2; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 30)
  - Dr. Sasha Buchman, Stanford University. GP-B Spacecraft at Vandenburg., undated; b30_3; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 30)
  - LISA Tech Dev. DEZ Sasha - 3 files, 2003; b30_4; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 30)
  - GPS Workshop - Images 101 - 152 @ Dr. Spilker's, 2002 Jul 21; b30_5; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 30)
  - The Launch Commemorative, 2004 Apr 20; b30_6; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 30)
  - Marshall Space Flight Center Document Repository: ITAR Restricted - Gravity Probe B PCB's, undated; b30_7; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 30)
  - LISA Tech Dev. DEZ Sasha - 3 files, 2003 Dec; b30_8; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 30)
  - Photos Integration, 2001 Oct 20; b30_9; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 30)
  - unlabeled disc, undated; b30_10; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 30)
  - LISA Tech Dev.Sasha Rev. A, undated; b30_11; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 30)
  - The Launch Commemorative, 2004 Apr 20; b30_12; 3 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 32)
  - Testing Einstein's Universe…and other information, second edition, 2004 Aug; b30_13; 3 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 32)
- Administrative records
  - SSR # 200714L GP-B DVD Addendum (slide printouts), undated; 0 (Box 31)
  - Gravity Probe B promotional material (booklets, posters, schematics), undated (Box 31)
  - GP-B Proposals, 1961-1962 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Leonard Schiff, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - GP-B Drag-Free (Early Papers), undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Non-disclosure of GP-B Data, undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Confidential Information, undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Bob Cannon, undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - George Mary Pugh, undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Pugh Lange History of Drag-Free, undated (Box 14, Folder 8)